WESLEY EL-AMIN

WEB DEVELOPER

✓ el-amin.7@buckeyemail.osu.edu↓ 317-270-2208in wesleyelamin♠ wesleye2003

About Me

Through my background in sales and psychology I have developed a deep interest in interpersonal relationships; my love for connecting people and helping them solve their problems is what drives me. I also recently graduated a coding trade school called Dev Bootcamp as a full stack web developer. My experiences there vastly improved my ability and desire to learn new things on the fly, and gave me a new passion for creating fun and efficient teams where people can easily communicate, collaborate, and thrive.

Experience

Full Stack Developer

Dev Bootcamp

Chicago, IL Jan 2016 to May 2016

- Built proficiency in multiple programming languages including Ruby, JavaScript, and HTML.
- Worked individually and on teams of up to 5 to build many meaningful database-backed apps, websites, and programs.
- Came up with an idea for a mobile application and led a team that developed the app from scratch.
- Solved many code puzzles using object oriented programming and test driven development.
- Developed a much deeper knowledge of team dynamics and interpersonal relationships.
- Learned to develop, publish, and share open source software.

Wireless Consultant

Verizon: The Cellular Connection

Gahanna, OH Nov 2015 to Jan 2016

- Learned to use proprietary sales tracking software including FIveStar and Zoho CRM.
- Consistently drove sales to over 100 new and current customers each month.

Sales Consultant

MarketSource, Inc.

Dublin, OH Jun 2015 to Sep 2015

- Acquired a much deeper understanding of cellular devices and the cellular industry.
- Created and maintained a neat, organized, and stable area in a fast-paced work environment.

Sales Associate

Micro Center

Columbus, OH May 2014 to May 2015

- Carried out regular cashier duties.
- Built a great amount of knowledge of computer parts, accessories, consumer electronics, networking systems, and more.
- Learned to troubleshoot various devices on the fly.
- Consistently exceeded \$1500 in sales each day and built a reputation as one of the highest performing salespeople in my department.

Front Desk Assistant

The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH Sep 2013 to Jan 2014

- Managed resident data in the student housing database.
- Empathized with residents and solved their problems as if they were my own.
- Assisted in planning community events.
- Assisted Resident Advisors and maintenance staff with the upkeep of the building.

Electrical Sales Associate

Menards. Inc.

Columbus, OH Mar 2012 to Jan 2013

- Received awards for outstanding customer service.
- Built, sold, and repaired electrical appliances.
- Became attuned to the needs of complete strangers by developing great listening skills and a heightened sense of empathy.

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS

Ruby

JavaScript

HTML5

CSS3

Sqlite3

Markdown

Ruby on Rails

PostgreSQL

Sinatra

Phaser.js

jQuery

RSpec Testing

Jasmine Framework

Testing

Capybara Testing

React

AngularJS

Ionic

PROGRAMMING PRINCIPLES

Object Oriented Design Pair Programming

Test Driven Development

Refactoring

OTHER SKILLS

Sales

Team Building

Microsoft Office

Customer Service

Orchestral and Jazz Music

Composition

Leadership

Troubleshooting

Public Speaking

Education

Dev BootcampWeb Development

The Ohio State University Psychology